[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c822", "question": "What brightly colored monkey is the world's largest?", "answer": "The mandrill", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ad9e209e748bb36357acdf8", "question": "What was Alfred Hitchcock\u2019s first American made film?", "answer": "Rebecca", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a2906c0f9723ab15cb43", "question": "Where was oldest sculpture of a human figure discovered?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a917", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Ticonderoga?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "590679b0ff9c0647b50a8050", "question": "On January 1, 2016, which Canadian province became the first one to allow the testing of self-driving vehicles on public roads?", "answer": "Ontario", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e92", "question": "What movie did the villain Joan Crawford appear in?", "answer": "Mommie Dearest", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c696", "question": "What US company invented fiberglass in 1938?", "answer": "Owens-Corning", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd14", "question": "What was the original brand of cereal whose mascot was CinnaMon?", "answer": "Apple Jacks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefbe7b6ce05a3942286ef1", "question": "Who first recorded the song \"Last Christmas\"?", "answer": "Wham!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbf806ce05a3942286f00", "question": "In the television series \"Magnum P.I.\", Magnum often wore a ball cap for which sport's team?", "answer": "Detroit Tigers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e1c", "question": "What TV show's announcer was Hank \"Hey Now!\" Kingsley?", "answer": "The Larry Sanders Show's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef93396ce05a3942286e8b", "question": "Frank Darabont seriously contemplated selling the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\" script to which person?", "answer": "Rob Reiner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8ce2994b094db915830a5", "question": "At what age did legendary English musician, Lemmy, die in 2015?", "answer": "70", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c95c", "question": "What is the common name for many species of burrowing mollusks?", "answer": "Clam", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b35891a5db0d66a186cb548", "question": "What word is used to identify the residents of Burkina Faso?", "answer": "Burkinabe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef96566ce05a3942286e9c", "question": "The novel \"Flowers for Algernon\" became which major motion picture?", "answer": "\"Charly\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af4a", "question": "What was the name of the first dog in space?", "answer": "Laika", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c554", "question": "Which gender has the XY chromosomes in human beings?", "answer": "Male", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec88e0ec223966ae8f8824", "question": "In 2011, which music superstar launched her own social media website?", "answer": "In 2011 Lady Gaga launched her \"Little Monsters\" social media network", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3231e5bf195a31e15d7389", "question": "Who owned the sword Joyeuse?", "answer": "Charlemagne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a86c", "question": "The Galapagos Islands are a province located in which country?", "answer": "Ecuador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fcb", "question": "What movie featured the fictional band \"The Soggy Bottom Boys\"?", "answer": "O Brother, Where Art Thou?", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb04", "question": "Which member of the British royal family was married to Sarah Ferguson?", "answer": "Prince Andrew", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e2fffe83fe1f2a824ba4", "question": "What was unique about the Doolittle Raid against Japan?", "answer": "The bombers took off from an aircraft carrier.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c95f", "question": "What is the study of soil called?", "answer": "Pedology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd81d1dd0de9af39e9d468b", "question": "What is the largest pyramid?", "answer": "Pyramid of Cholula", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b40201dd7bf43be5e7b9", "question": "What library has the most books in the U.S.?", "answer": "The Library of Congress", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c9f706b4e2c7fbd3896745", "question": "What is Kahlua flavored with?", "answer": "Coffee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5f6c6ce05a3942286e42", "question": "Where is Paddington Bear from?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c693", "question": "What do astronomers call an interstellar cloud of dust dust, hydrogen, helium and other ionized gases?", "answer": "Nebula", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c9f", "question": "In \"The Wizard of Oz\", what was Dorothy's uncle's name?", "answer": "Henry", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae64", "question": "On July 4, 1776, how many English colonies proclaimed a Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "13", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b5", "question": "Which movie star published an autobiography in 2002 entitled \"Lucky Man\"?", "answer": "Michael J. Fox", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b46c", "question": "Which two individuals were the first to reach the summit of Mount Everest in 1953?", "answer": "Sir Edmund Hillary and Tenzing Norgay", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c252", "question": "What is 11 squared?", "answer": "121", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e94d1fc5ea27d7a1303aed6", "question": "In what US state is the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Massachusetts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339882", "question": "In The Hobbit, how many dwarves show up at Bilbos house?", "answer": "13", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c92f", "question": "Our galaxy is commonly known by what name?", "answer": "Milky Way", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5904a4c7cf93664eb10486c6", "question": "Shortly after meeting David, which North American city did Katchoo disappear to for 2 months, in the comic series \"Strangers in Paradise\"?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58f168fcf7c52aae91cc07cc", "question": "In what film did Elvis play a double role?", "answer": "Kissin' Cousins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8e0", "question": "Who christened Hawaii \"the Sandwich Islands\" in 1778?", "answer": "Captain Cook", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339219", "question": "What actor is known as \"The Fonz\"?", "answer": "Henry Winkler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdab5a20b8cce1e6fda704e", "question": "An \"agelast\" is someone who never does what?", "answer": "Laughs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133891e", "question": "In which issue of the comic series \"Tales of Suspense\" did Iron Man first appear?", "answer": "39", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b850", "question": "How many Justices are there on the US Supreme Court?", "answer": "9", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe90a9401dd7bf43be5e89d", "question": "In 1901, Guglielmo Marconi received the first transatlantic wireless signal from atop Signal Hill in which city?", "answer": "St. John's, Newfoundland", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c02d", "question": "To determine the percentage of alcohol in a bottle of liquor, what is divided by two?", "answer": "Proof", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c9f78cb4e2c7fbd389674a", "question": "What popular French apple brandy is made by distilling cider made from selected apples?", "answer": "Calvados", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2fb", "question": "Who has held the world record in the pole vault, 6.14 m, for more than twenty years?", "answer": "Sergei Bubka", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe522a01bf59ab7d2e380e8", "question": "Who did Nicolas Cage marry in 2002?", "answer": "Lisa Marie Presley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133962f", "question": "\"Three's Company\" is an American remake of which British sitcom?", "answer": "Man about the House", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae9263574a5ce6b56b822c", "question": "How many pieces of bun are in a Mcdonald's Big Mac?", "answer": "Three", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5906826dff9c0647b50a809d", "question": "What physical, interactive feature did Apple introduce to their MacBook Pro laptop series in the fall of 2016?", "answer": "The \"Touch Bar\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b754", "question": "How many points are E and O each worth in a Scrabble game?", "answer": "One", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec234a8dc25ca9e12ef62f", "question": "By what name is \"Calcium oxide\" more commonly known?", "answer": "Quicklime", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5bb", "question": "What type of milk is traditional feta cheese made of?", "answer": "Sheep's milk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b602", "question": "The cover of what band's 1977 album \"Animals\" depicts a large, inflatable pig flying over London's Battersea Power Station?", "answer": "Pink Floyd", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae7b", "question": "What island was the scene of a nuclear accident in 1979?", "answer": "Three Mile Island", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133994d", "question": "What sitcom star\u2019s parents were named Morty and Helen on his TV show?", "answer": "Jerry Seinfeld", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f4", "question": "What US state has been governed by Gifford Pinchot and Milton Shapp?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ab", "question": "George H.W. Bush served in which branch of the US military?", "answer": "Navy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339613", "question": "What sport was featured in the 1985 movie \"Vision Quest\"?", "answer": "Wrestling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59bb2a7cc9bff04efae6d760", "question": "From which country did the US buy the United States Virgin Islands in 1916?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b865", "question": "What is the only bird to be honored by its own year on the Chinese calendar?", "answer": "Rooster", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a952", "question": "What is the only US state that ends with the state's own postal abbreviation?", "answer": "Kentucky", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef61c86ce05a3942286e58", "question": "In which U.S. state was Taylor Swift born?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6007815fbd51d85e222ab64b", "question": "What art movement employs aspects of mass culture, such as advertising, comic books and mundane cultural objects?", "answer": "Seeking to elevate popular culture to the level of fine art,\u00a0Pop artists\u00a0celebrated commonplace objects and everyday people.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b83a", "question": "What food got its name by the way it hung in bunches like grapes?", "answer": "Grapefruit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c6d", "question": "What are the names of the four Musketeers?", "answer": "Athos, Aramis, Porthos and D\u2019artagnan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339223", "question": "What is the name of Futurama's first episode aired in 1999?", "answer": "Space Pilot 3000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad05", "question": "Where were the 1996 Summer Olympics held?", "answer": "Atlanta, Georgia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ff", "question": "What do opposite faces of a die always add up to?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65869ae7e414034b5aeef", "question": "Who was the leading ace for Norway in WWII?", "answer": "Svein Heglund", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d47071f8e329de4f877891", "question": "What year was cricketer Phil Tufnell born?", "answer": "1966", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c6440775fa611bce67d0", "question": "Singapore's Marina Bay Sands hotel is home to the world's highest what?", "answer": "Swimming pool -- The hotel has on its rooftop an enormous infinity pool.  At 650 feet, it is the world's  highest swimming pool.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133903a", "question": "Under what pen name did Hector Hugh Munro write?", "answer": "Saki", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec9", "question": "Who was the US vice-president during the presidency of Bill Clinton?", "answer": "Al Gore", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339668", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who is Radioactive Man's boy sidekick?", "answer": "Fallout Boy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f98", "question": "What character from a pop song wears electric boots and a mohair suit?", "answer": "Bennie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59564403803c1f1ebcc4a033", "question": "Ketchup was sold in the 1830\u2019s as what?", "answer": "Medicine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa3", "question": "What do the Plastics call their \"slam book\" in the 2004 movie \"Mean Girls\"?", "answer": "The Burn Book", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a200", "question": "Who was the very first actor to win two consecutive Best Actor Oscars?", "answer": "Spencer Tracy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d77", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"The Children's Crusade\"?", "answer": "Slaughterhouse-Five", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59f9b7a7364247bf200fb874", "question": "Who had a hit in 1988 with the song \"I Get Weak\"?", "answer": "Belinda Carlisle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133969b", "question": "What does Martin Blank do for a living in the 1997 movie \"Grosse Point Blank\"?", "answer": "He is a hitman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339874", "question": "In Disney's \"The Jungle Book\", what is King Louie's greatest desire?", "answer": "To obtain fire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a6dd20565ad31a57c7e0", "question": "Who was the founding commandant of the Nazi concentration camp Auschwitz?", "answer": "Rudolph H\u00f6ss", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395bf", "question": "When the Simpsons go camping, where does Maggie spend her first night?", "answer": "With bears in a cave", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4bb", "question": "What is the only nation that borders both Ecuador and Bolivia?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef61266ce05a3942286e50", "question": "The Simpsons\" got its start as filler material on which show?", "answer": "\"Tbe Tracy Ullman Show\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a059", "question": "\"Run\" is a 1994 Hong Kong remake of which shoe string-budget action film by Robert Rodriguez?", "answer": "El Mariachi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c4a6fbde8045e484669f", "question": "Which small African mammal keeps a watch-duty rotation throughout the day?", "answer": "Meerkat -- One, called the sentry, will keep a watch for predators by standing on its hind legs.  They rotate who is on watch.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339040", "question": "Who wrote a book entitled \"The Adventures of Lord Iffy Boatrace\"?", "answer": "Bruce Dickinson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be37", "question": "How many players are there in a standard soccer team?", "answer": "Eleven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede2d96ce05a3942286dce", "question": "Who wrote, sang, and played the instruments for \"Wonderful Christmastime\"?", "answer": "Paul McCartney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd7ecec223966ae8f88d9", "question": "Simone Biles was the first woman to do what in official competition?", "answer": "Land a triple-double", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4ddd206d333868d34d709", "question": "Besides \"Axis Sally\", who was another famous propaganda broadcaster for the Nazis?", "answer": "Berlin Betty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf58", "question": "What do the letters A and W stand for in the \"A&W\" root beer name?", "answer": "Allen and Wright", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2dc", "question": "Who was Arthur Jefferson's comedy partner?", "answer": "Oliver Hardy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea0", "question": "What chocolate cake is named for the Vienna hotel that keeps its recipe secret?", "answer": "Sachertorte", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133926f", "question": "How much does the Academy Award statue weigh?", "answer": "8.5 pounds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ac", "question": "What mountain is the tallest point in Canada?", "answer": "Logan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b314", "question": "Who rode his horse Copenhagen at the Battle of Waterloo?", "answer": "The Duke of Wellington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba2c", "question": "Which US state's official flower is the Saguato Cactus?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a151", "question": "Who was the first female to be inducted into the Rock and Roll Hall Of Fame?", "answer": "Aretha Franklin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1bb", "question": "At the 1996 Olympics, what American tied Mark Spitz's lifetime record of nine golds?", "answer": "Carl Lewis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed8", "question": "What is raku?", "answer": "Type of Japanese pottery", "category": "general"}, {"id": "593c4ba4b8198b9a2b077965", "question": "Who is Scarlett's first husband who died in the Civil War in \"Gone with the Wind\"?", "answer": "Charles Hamilton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a46d", "question": "Which is the longest river in the United Kingdom?", "answer": "Severn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec89acec223966ae8f8829", "question": "\"Fear takes flight\" is the tagline for what 2005 film?", "answer": "\"Red Eye\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec2", "question": "In medieval times, what was an Iron Maiden used for?", "answer": "Torture", "category": "history"}, {"id": "593c4abab8198b9a2b07795e", "question": "Who is Lightning McQueen's love interest in Disney's film \"Cars\"?", "answer": "Sally Carrera", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc2", "question": "By tradition, what can you call yourself if you were born within the sound of London's Bow bells ringing?", "answer": "Cockney", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6a6fe6c0f9723ab15cb59", "question": "What does \"A.D.\" stand for, in reference to dates?", "answer": "Anno Domini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a899dc260d398dc9cf7a6ae", "question": "Which year did Henry Kissinger receive the Nobel Peace Prize?", "answer": "1973", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6012188e63c99d48cd169af5", "question": "What do you call a group of unicorns?", "answer": "A blessing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a23a", "question": "What Australian rock band release the album \"Business as Usual\" in 1981?", "answer": "Men at Work", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c5a40775fa611bce67ca", "question": "The spice paprika is made from what?", "answer": "Sweet pepper pods -- Paprika is made from ground sweet pepper pods that are dried and powdered.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133957e", "question": "What game was played for money by the Vietnamese in \"The Deer Hunter\" movie?", "answer": "Russian Roulette", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078b640eee65b76b9f2667", "question": "Which seven U.S. states seceded and formed the original Confederacy during the U.S. Civil War?", "answer": "Alabama, Florida, Georgia, Louisiana, Mississippi, South Carolina and Texas.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f1", "question": "What is the alter ego of the superhero known as the Amazing Spider-Man?", "answer": "Peter Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071fe43745b36be73039ed", "question": "What does an Advent calendar count down to?", "answer": "Christmas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad20", "question": "Which confectioner invented the heart-shaped Valentine's Day candy box?", "answer": "Richard Cadbury", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bdb", "question": "What is Mark Wahlberg's famous nickname?", "answer": "Markymark", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a7", "question": "What George Orwell book foresees Oceania, Eurasia and Eastasia?", "answer": "1984", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133920c", "question": "In which TV show is the local fast-food restaurant called \"The Chum Bucket\"?", "answer": "SpongeBob SquarePants", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51247ff04d658268c92ce", "question": "Cleopatra represented herself as the reincarnation of what Egyptian goddess?", "answer": "Cleopatra represented herself as the reincarnation of the Egyptian goddess\u00a0Isis.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339765", "question": "How does Kyra Collins die in the Sixth Sense?", "answer": "She is poisoned", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937eab508d98002fdd633a7", "question": "Easter Island is part of which South American country?", "answer": "Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fc2f443cee580c7f8fd1e57", "question": "What country has the largest tar pit?", "answer": "Trinidad and Tobago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c0", "question": "How many toes do ostriches have on each foot?", "answer": "2", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339987", "question": "What Beatles single lasted longest on the charts, at 19 weeks?", "answer": "Hey Jude", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c61c", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Helium?", "answer": "He", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600b880a1d8c1817608d53ed", "question": "In mathematics, what term describes the bottom number in a fraction?", "answer": "Denominator", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ad7ebeeb24f84e0b9f9ffe1", "question": "The song \"Honolulu Baby\" appears in which Laurel and Hardy film?", "answer": "Sons of the Desert", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339537", "question": "Where does Grace work in the TV show \"Grace Under Fire\"?", "answer": "At the oil refinery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339192", "question": "Who is Garfield's owner?", "answer": "Jon Arbuckle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd4a", "question": "By US law, exit signs in buildings must be one of what two colors?", "answer": "Red or green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51b7aff04d658268c930e", "question": "What singers lure sailors to crash on the rocks with their songs?", "answer": "Circe warned Odysseus of the Sirens, bird-like women whose beautiful singing caused sailors to crash to their death.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef61c06ce05a3942286e57", "question": "Jennifer Lopez started her career on which television show?", "answer": "\"In Living Color\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6c7", "question": "The resort city of Aspen is located in which US state?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c4d", "question": "What year was Robert Downey Jr.'s first movie, \"Pound\" released in?", "answer": "1970", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e9ae8ebfabb9c85d8a980", "question": "The \"Althing\" is the national parliament of which country?", "answer": "Iceland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff66e6952a821ff76ae8b1b", "question": "What did people often say for photos before \"cheese\"?", "answer": "When Richard Beard, Britain's first portrait photographer, began taking family portraits, he told his clients to say \"prunes\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef2ede6ce05a3942286dfd", "question": "When did Vladimir Lenin serve as the head of the Soviet Russia?", "answer": "1917 to 1922", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c87b877e98cb977789e6", "question": "In which country can you find Piedra del Pe\u00f1ol (also called El Pe\u00f1on de Guatape)?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339217", "question": "What Stealers Wheel hit is heard in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Stuck in the Middle with You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a18", "question": "What Italian town takes tourists to the workshop of renowned stringent-instrument maker Antonio Stradivari?", "answer": "Cremona", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a05e", "question": "\"I melt with you\" was which band's signature hit released on their \"After the Snow\"?", "answer": "Modern English", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abe9", "question": "Oil wrestling is the national sport of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ae85ed44007905755f79e8a", "question": "Epee, Sabre and Foil are all types of what?", "answer": "Swords (Fencing Sport)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5fd", "question": "Which mint was the first to be used as a gum flavoring by the Wrigley Company?", "answer": "Spearmint", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af0d", "question": "What nickname was given to General Thomas J. Jackson during the Civil War?", "answer": "\"Stonewall\" Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefbea56ce05a3942286ef4", "question": "Which rock band performed at President Bill Clinton's first inauguration?", "answer": "Fleetwood Mac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9e0", "question": "What term is given to the scientific study of all aspects of the life of fungi?", "answer": "Mycology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e72cce8d0874f1a5e2d1c25", "question": "What is a \"Winkle Picker\" or \"Winklepicker\"?", "answer": "An English long pointed shoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6008dd25f4f3bc4a292f861e", "question": "Mother Teresa received the Nobel Peace Prize for what?", "answer": "Peace, or more accurately \"for work undertaken in the struggle to overcome poverty and distress, which also constitutes a threat to peace\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c77cf2f24f0f7a362efd54c", "question": "How many claws in total does the average adult cat have?", "answer": "18", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398a3", "question": "Who directed the movie \"The Passion of the Christ\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c831", "question": "The \"Wandering\" species of what bird has the longest wingspan in nature?", "answer": "Albatross", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388be", "question": "What food of the three bears did Goldilocks eat?", "answer": "Porridge", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a156", "question": "Who is Gordon Sumner better known as?", "answer": "Sting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133964a", "question": "What planet is home to the Jedi Temple?", "answer": "Coruscant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133998a", "question": "What rocker was backed by a band called \"Crazy Horse\"?", "answer": "Neil Young", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b885e662d71a53651025", "question": "Which German painter was sometimes court painter to King Henry VIII of England after 1536?", "answer": "Hans Holbein the Younger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6010c7e20775fa611bce67dd", "question": "Why do penny loafers have a slot for a coin?", "answer": "For a payphone -- Penny loafers allowed schoolchildren to always have two pennies if they needed to make an emergency call home.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e3", "question": "What year was the first Amazon Kindle device introduced?", "answer": "2007", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f30524f5aa2bc17b61b2ac9", "question": "What is the capital of Moldova?", "answer": "Chi\u0219in\u0103u", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c021", "question": "Which fashion designer was shot dead in the summer of 1997?", "answer": "Gianni Versace", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c716", "question": "What astronomical unit of distance equals about 5.88 trillion miles?", "answer": "1 light year", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bfe0045b668d7dfe168b5c0", "question": "Which desert is located in the southeastern part of California?", "answer": "The Mojave desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a727", "question": "Which six states share a border with Idaho?", "answer": "Washington, Oregon, Nevada, Utah, Wyoming and Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a0", "question": "According to the Gospels, what did the Wise Men bring?", "answer": "Gold, Frankincense, and Myrrh", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596dfee79616e6c6d4eba4fd", "question": "The Artful Dodger is a character from which novel? ", "answer": "Oliver Twist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b188", "question": "Who succeeded Jimmy Carter as the 40th President of the United States?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c988", "question": "What is the name given to a group of geese?", "answer": "Gaggle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe36ba60ada16518afdc03d", "question": "Which music mogul was involved in creating \"RocaWear\"?", "answer": "Jay-Z", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a0c", "question": "What is the name of the gypsy girl who Quasimodo fell in love with?", "answer": "Esmeralda", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594d07e91a1c922dd1ac64bd", "question": "Which Science Fiction author wrote \"The Day of the Triffids\"?", "answer": "John Wyndham", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9d7", "question": "How many squares are on a chessboard?", "answer": "64", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae77", "question": "To what tribe did Chief Tecumseh belong?", "answer": "Shawnee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b09a", "question": "Which English King signed the Magna Carta in 1215?", "answer": "King John", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d49", "question": "What year did The Louvre open as a museum?", "answer": "1793", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59bb2a42c9bff04efae6d75e", "question": "What was writer Eric Arthur Blair's pen name?", "answer": "George Orwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bada", "question": "What brand of cat food was advertised by Morris the Cat?", "answer": "9 Lives", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec26898dc25ca9e12ef64c", "question": "How many engines are on a B-52 bomber?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e2", "question": "What fruit comes in Redhaven and Harmony variety?", "answer": "Peaches", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a3c8319039f3d7859290ff7", "question": "In the TV Show \"Bonanza\", what was Ben Cartwright\u2019s profession prior to moving to Nevada and buying the Ponderosa?", "answer": "Ship\u2019s chandler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e3", "question": "What was the middle name of composer Bach?", "answer": "Sebastian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feba9337e83c707845b20d3", "question": "What is the scientific name of the plant used to make liquorice?", "answer": "Glycyrrhiza Glabra", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a88120565ad31a57c7f6", "question": "Which American author was awarded both the Nobel Prize in Literature and Presidential Medal of Freedom?", "answer": "John Steinbeck", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdc0c99469bb8041d07a053", "question": "What type of horse is named from the Spanish word meaning \"painted\"?", "answer": "Pinto", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b2", "question": "What athlete played co-pilot Roger Murdock in the 1980 movie \"Airplane!\"?", "answer": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c028d3fea32143fcb1d3b57", "question": "Who created the \"Dragonriders Of Pern\" series?", "answer": "Anne McCaffrey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f39dff048f679a45aac1", "question": "What color is liquid oxygen?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b571c9167df192a942e3376", "question": "What is Pele's birth name?", "answer": "Edson Arantes do Nascimento", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea43b2ff048f679a45ab86", "question": "What is the largest kangaroo?", "answer": "The red kangaroo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef61b26ce05a3942286e56", "question": "Which Spice Girl was Victoria Beckham?", "answer": "Posh Spice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbef", "question": "Who designed Madonna's infamous cone-bra?", "answer": "Jean Paul Gaultier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a374", "question": "What is the capital of Romania?", "answer": "Bucharest", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d8", "question": "What is the eastern-most US state capital?", "answer": "Augusta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921c", "question": "What city did the band U2 form in?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4cb", "question": "Which New England state doesn't border the Atlantic Ocean?", "answer": "Vermont", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9b2", "question": "What team did Vince Lombardi coach to two Super Bowl victories?", "answer": "Green Bay Packers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a25f2426682715b82711ce9", "question": "Feijoada, the national dish of Brazil, originates from which European country?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdad", "question": "What food item shares its name with Brad and Janet's hospitable host in \"The Rocky Horror Picture Show\"?", "answer": "A frankfurter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f9a", "question": "What character from a pop song wears a screwed-down hairdo and snow-white tan?", "answer": "Ziggy Stardust", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f6bc01dd7bf43be5e833", "question": "What Apple product was code-named Dulcimer during its development?", "answer": "iPod", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca27", "question": "What is the medical term for fainting?", "answer": "Syncope", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59774586284458f1d7854436", "question": "What ancient Greek god/goddess represented Necromancy?", "answer": "Hecate", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b971", "question": "Which variations brought lasting fame for Sir Edward Elgar?", "answer": "Enigma Variations", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c263", "question": "What grows in a paddy field?", "answer": "Rice", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cdd69e347d002c297e4f0", "question": "What are affected by Phylloxera?", "answer": "Grapevines", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339395", "question": "Which actor from the cast of the movie \"Rain Man\" won an Oscar?", "answer": "Dustin Hoffmann", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d60", "question": "Who played the role of TV's T..J. Hooker?", "answer": "William Shatner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c58f", "question": "During which time period did the stegosaurus walk the earth?", "answer": "Late Jurassic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb3", "question": "What Big US East school took the cryptic name for its sports teams from the Greek word for \"what\"?", "answer": "Georgetown", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ae9319574a5ce6b56b8235", "question": "Who was the Greek goddess of youth?", "answer": "Hebe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133917b", "question": "Whose author's novel is the movie \"The Godfather\" based on?", "answer": "Mario Puzo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ad", "question": "Who recorded the international hit single \"Poker Face\" in 2008?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339226", "question": "What country provided most of the settings for \"The Lord of the Rings\" movies?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ab", "question": "What postal code has Canada Post assigned to Santa Claus's residence at the North Pole?", "answer": "H0H 0H0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a09d", "question": "Where was \"Can't Buy Me Love\" recorded?", "answer": "Paris, France", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e1b", "question": "Who began his famous penance by killing and skinning the Nemean lion?", "answer": "Hercules", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd822e5d0de9af39e9d46ac", "question": "How many vice presidents did FDR have during his time in office?", "answer": "3", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f30dff048f679a45aabc", "question": "How far is Earth from the center of the Milky Way Galaxy?", "answer": "25,000 light years", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b37c", "question": "Who was the 15th President of the US?", "answer": "James Buchanan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c5", "question": "Who shot President James Garfield?", "answer": "Charles J. Guiteau", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a3", "question": "Who was the second man to set foot on the Moon?", "answer": "Buzz Aldrin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b14", "question": "What color is the little engine in the children's book \"The Little Engine That Could\"?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ccf78d0b37b32637bdc44bb", "question": "What is the name of Marvin and Trina's son in the musical \"Falsettos\"?", "answer": "Jason", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b124", "question": "Which war included an infantry assault known as Pickett's Charge?", "answer": "American Civil War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b10c", "question": "In what year did both the Titanic sink and Fenway Park in Boston opened?", "answer": "1912", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b875", "question": "What make of car appears in the left foreground of the \"Abbey Road\" cover?", "answer": "Volkswagen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339755", "question": "Who played Sam Spade in the 1941 movie \"The Maltese Falcon\"?", "answer": "Humphrey Bogart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c810", "question": "A deficiency of which vitamin can lead to night blindness?", "answer": "A", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef92e66ce05a3942286e88", "question": "Who is the first mainstream artist known for utilizing the infamous Auto-Tune vocal distortion technique?", "answer": "Cher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f0ecff048f679a45aaab", "question": "Verminophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Germs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58dba37d874c93a3298b213c", "question": "What additional part does someone with Polyorhidism have?", "answer": "Extra testicle(s)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f5d", "question": "In what year did Abe Vigoda from the TV show \"Barney Miller\" die?", "answer": "2016", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe93ac66bd93ce3a4e5f69b", "question": "What is the scientific study of animal biology?", "answer": "Zoology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c9", "question": "The March of Dimes was originally founded to help find a vaccine for what?", "answer": "Polio", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fbaed190738315b1fb74e2e", "question": "In what year did the first president of Kenya die?", "answer": "1978", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909cbb9bb53d1af658864da", "question": "Which artist recorded the Christmas song \"Run Rudolph Run\" in 1958?", "answer": "Chuck Berry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c115", "question": "What city was Canadian figure skater, Elvis Stojko, born?", "answer": "Newmarket", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec22878dc25ca9e12ef628", "question": "In which city can you find the famed Arch of Hadrian?", "answer": "Ahtens, Greece", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb72", "question": "What was pictured on the face of the US penny just prior to Abraham Lincoln?", "answer": "Indian head", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f74b0a9e54d890926f6fd", "question": "In St. Louis, Missouri, it\u2019s illegal for a firefighter to rescue whom?", "answer": "Undressed women (even if they are wearing a nightgown)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd66d47a5bfecdd737e089e", "question": "What is the most valuable stock exchange in the world?", "answer": "New York Stock Exchange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909cd15bb53d1af658864e6", "question": "How many times does the word \"jingle\" appear in the first verse of \"Jingle Bells\"?", "answer": "Three", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6018bc25d96d05b23b281653", "question": "\"An eye for an eye and a tooth for a tooth\" is a well-known phrase from what collection of 282 laws?", "answer": "The Code of Hammurabi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a063", "question": "Before becoming a singer, what was Perry Como's profession?", "answer": "Barber", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2db", "question": "What do ladybugs feed on during hibernation?", "answer": "Stored fat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e61", "question": "Who provided the original voice for The Iron Giant?", "answer": "Vin Diesel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ae", "question": "The April 13, 1919 Jallianwala Bagh Massacre of civilians by British troops is also known by what other name?", "answer": "The Amritsar Massacre", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e6bbbdfb6c85e9e634ff58", "question": "What is short for \"light amplification by stimulated emission of radiation\"?", "answer": "Laser", "category": "science"}]